### **DENNIS GATUHA**

0715 199 778 P.O Box 52-20104, Menengai West

#### PROFFESIONAL SUMMARY

A self-motivated Food Science practitioner with over 3 years industry experience in a fast-paced, healthy foods dealing set up. I boast of hands-on experience in regulatory compliance, on-process product checks, new products development, root cause analysis, integrated pest management among others. I am looking for an opening in an organization that will exploit my skillset while helping me gain new skills or advance on the existing.

### SKILLS AND KEY COMPETENCIES

- Regulatory compliance
- New Product development
- RCA
- Pest management
- SAP proficiency
- ICT competent
- Team player

### **EDUCATION**

Nov 2013-Dec 2017: B.Sc. Food Processing Technology, Upper second class, Masinde Muliro University of Science and Technology

Feb 2009-Nov 2012: Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE), Kirobon Boys High School, B-Plain

Jan 2001-Nov 2008: Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (KCPE), Mang'u Primary School, 298/500 marks

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Quality Assurance Officer,**

### Healthy U 2000 Ltd, Feb 2019 to date.

- ➤ Overseeing local and international regulatory compliance
- ➤ Developing and implementing Quality-related SOPs
- ➤ Co-chairing the company's product development team.
- > Conducting HACCP analysis on various products.
- > Inspection of raw materials and packaging materials to ascertain quality.
- Monitoring production process to ensure conformity to local and global standards.

- > Investigating customer complaints and conducting RCA analysis.
- > Developing and implementing quality policies and SOPs.
- > Conduct quality audits on the healthy U shops.
- > Identify training needs and organize training interventions on company staff to meet quality standards
- ➤ Coordinate and support on-site audits conducted by external providers
- ➤ Monitor risk management activities
- Responsible for quality document management systems
- Ensure ongoing compliance with quality and industry regulatory requirements
- > Oversee that proper housekeeping and hygiene are maintained in all work areas.
- Inspection of market returns to segregate items for disposal and rework.
- > Inspection of stock rotation items to verify the quality.
- > Supervising and monitoring the disposal process and waste management.
- Inspection and testing of new product samples from new suppliers.
- Monitoring the stock management in the warehouse by routine checks on expiry dates of items stocked.
- > Supervising pest control treatments conducted in the warehouse.
- ➤ Observation of the QC received samples on routine basis and recording findings.

# Rift Valley and Western Kenya Correspondent www.ragahouse.com, June 2017- Dec 2018

## Duties and responsibilities

- Attend rugby matches and write match reports on the same
- Interview various rugby stakeholders in my area of duty
- Write opinion articles on trending topics in rugby circles

### **Research assistant-attachment**

### Kenya Industrial Research and Development Institute (KIRDI), June 2016-Aug 2016

### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Carried out quality tests on various food samples
- Undertook in the manufacturing and packaging of juices, noodles and sauces
- Housekeeping of laboratory facilities
- Did baking of confectionery e.g. breads, cakes and biscuits

## **REFEREES**

Paul Wanjohi Quality Assurance Manager Healthy U 2000 Ltd qa@healthy-u2000.com +254 721819374

Michael Mukholwe Lecturer, Masinde Muliro University of Science and Technology 020-234235 mmukholwe@mmust.ac.ke

Erick Njiru Senior Writer, www.Ragahouse.com 0726 206 521 Erick@ragahouse.com